

MOHAMMED RISHAD V K

Senior Software Engineer (Python, Django, Flask, Postgres, RestAPI, AWS, Docker)

More than 5 years of experience working with Scalable, Reusable, Reliable, Object Oriented Programming(OOP), Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) in Software Development. I'm a quick learner and highly flexible to adapt to new challenges, take ownership, handle multiple responsibilities and mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer, StudySmarter UG

MUNICH, GERMANY (REMOTE FROM INDIA)

Dec 2021 - Present

Senior Software Engineer, Reckonsys Tech Labs Pvt. Ltd

BENGALURU. KARNATAKA. INDIA

May 2019 - Nov 2021

- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the business to implement features and understand use cases.
- Contribute to design and development of Backend and API's
- Contribute to functional definition of customer requirements.
- Meeting with the customer to discuss requirements(US, Europe, India).
- Contribute to the technical design and development APIs with performance and scalability in mind.
- Research, suggest and implement new solutions in performance of backend service.
- Integration of third-party API's and creating webhooks for the business.
- Experience with devops and infrastructure practices and technology like CI, deployment automation, provisioning, Amazon AWS.
- Mentoring and training new joinees and juniors.
- Some industries worked are Hotel, Sports, Hiring, Transport, Aviation, Healthcare, Analytics, Travel, etc.

Technologies

 Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, Postgres, HTML, CSS, GraphQL, RestAPI, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Elixir / Phoenix, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, SES, CloudFront, IAM, ACM, EC2, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Clients

 ClipHire, Moonllight, TransportSimple, Vigna, Acumen Aviation, Kiplist, D8aDriven, NuFlights

Software Engineer, SayOne Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA

Feb 2018 - May 2019

- Help to develop 5+ web applications from scratch.
- Managed team of 4 members including Backend and Frontend Developers.

Malappuram, Kerala India, 676510 +91(0)9567802281 mohammedrishad.vk@gmail.com

LINKS

- Website
- LinkedIn
- Github
- StackOverflow

SKILLS

Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, GraphQL, RestAPI, CSS, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, HTML, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Git, AWS, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, Heroku, Linux(Ubuntu),

Familiar:

Java, C/C++, JQuery, Elixir, Phoenix, Node.js, Express JS, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, XML, JSON, Elastic Search, Numpy, Pandas, Mac OS, Windows, Terraform, Kafka, Data Structures, Algorithms

AWARDS & HONORS

SayOne Rockstar – Best Performer (Dec 2018).

Winner Djangothon2018 by HackerEarth (1st Prize Winner).

Acknowledged by Google, Microsoft, Sony, Freelancer, Kaspersky, eBay, CRIS, etc. for reporting security bugs.

LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient, C1)
- German (Beginner, A1)
- Malayalam (Native, C2)

- Developed a highly scalable ecommerce SaaS platform for independent pet retailers with Django and Postgres. (Worked on DB Design, Dashboard(Role, Orders, Invoicing, Products, Theming, Coupon, Offers) and Frontend Pages, etc)
- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the business to implement features and understand use cases.
- Developed Chrome / Firefox Browser extension for article rating tool with Diango.
- Developed and maintained an article website for big data, blockchain, and artificial intelligence with insights and job opportunities using Django.

Technologies

Python / Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 TypeScript, Angular, Celery, Redis, Elastic Search, RestAPI, Git,
 SendGrid

Clients

o <u>eTailPet</u>, <u>FeedMyFurBaby</u>, <u>Datafloq</u>, <u>Mavin</u>, <u>BeCo</u>, <u>ProteinForPets</u>,

Python Developer, CogniCor Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

- Involved in the development of Chatbot and Dashboard using Python 2.7,
 Django 1.8, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, MongoDB.
- Build Analytics Dashboard to help the team to analyze/visualize chats and leads.
- Build Chatbot custom flows with Django forms.
- Created periodic bank account statements for Federal Bank.
- Closely worked with banks and Insurance companies to collect chatbot requirements.
- Technologies
 - Python, Django, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Git
- Clients
 - o ICICI Bank, OCBC Bank, Federal Bank, Tata Capital, Atos.

EDUCATION

University of Calicut — M.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA 2014 - 2016

- Blue Card Eligible EU / German
- Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 7.13/10 (71.3 %) A grade

University of Calicut — B.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA 2011 - 2014

Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 2.76/4 (69 %) - B grade

INTERESTS

- Open Source Contribution
- Competitive Programming
- Web Security Research
- Mentoring
- Continuous Learning
- Photography
- Travel
- Football (Soccer)